The most terrifying scream is always the last.
Scream 3 is a horror, mystery film directed by Wes Craven.
As bodies begin dropping around the Hollywood set of STAB 3, the third film based on the gruesome Woodsboro
killings, Sidney and other survivors are once again terrorized by another Ghostface killer.
Dewey Riley, played by David Arquette.
Sidney Prescott, played by Neve Campbell.
Gale Weathers, played by Courteney Cox.
Mark Kincaid, played by Patrick Dempsey.
Roman Bridger, played by Scott Foley.
John Milton, played by Lance Henriksen.
Scream 3 is a 2000 American slasher film directed by
Wes Craven and written by Ehren Kruger.
It stars David Arquette, Neve Campbell, Courteney Cox Arquette, Parker Posey, Patrick Dempsey, Scott Foley, Lance
Henriksen, Matt Keeslar, Jenny McCarthy, Emily Mortimer, Deon Richmond, and Patrick Warburton.
It is a sequel to Scream 2 (1997) and the third
installment in the Scream film series.
The film's story follows Sidney Prescott (Campbell), who has gone into self-imposed isolation following the events of the previous
two films but is drawn to Hollywood after a new Ghostface begins killing the cast of the film within a film Stab 3.
Scream 3 combines the violence of the slasher genre with comedy and
"whodunit" mystery, while satirizing the cliché of film trilogies.
Unlike the previous Scream films, there was an increased emphasis on comedic elements in this installment; the violence and horror were
reduced in response to increased public scrutiny about violence in media, following the Columbine High School massacre.
Scream (1996) screenwriter Kevin Williamson provided a five-page outline for two sequels to Scream when
auctioning his original script, hoping to entice bidders with the potential of buying a franchise.
Williamson's commitments to other projects meant he was unable to develop a complete script for Scream 3,
so writing duties were undertaken by Kruger, who discarded many of Williamson's notes.
Craven and Marco Beltrami returned to direct and score the film, respectively.
Production was troubled, including script rewrites, occasions when pages were only ready
on the day of filming, and scheduling difficulties with the main cast.
Principal photography took place from July to September 1999,
and the ending was re-filmed in January 2000.
Scream 3 premiered on February 3, 2000, in Westwood, Los Angeles, and was theatrically released
the following day, grossing $161.8 million worldwide on a budget of $40 million.
The film received mixed reviews but has been reappraised in
recent years in the wake of the MeToo movement.
Scream 3 was originally intended to be the final installment of the series until the
franchise was revived with a sequel, Scream 4, released on April 15, 2011.
The film explores themes of mask, isolation, movie business, ex-cop, sequel.
The tone is dark and mind_bending.